Inventory of the Chinese Cultural Revolution collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Newspapers, 1966-1976 (Boxes 1-14)
  - Zhi ba chun lai bao 只把春来报 [N.p.], 首都中学生革命造反统一战线宣传组编, 1967 February-June (Box-folder 14: 28)
  - Zhi dian jiang shan 指点江山 [天津], 天津东风大学八一八最高指示宣传组指点江山编辑部, 1967 April 24 (Box-folder 14: 29)
  - Zhi jiao zhan bao 职教战报 [上海], 上海市职工业余学校教师革命委员会职革会, 1967 April 30 (Box-folder 14: 30)
  - Zhi zheng zhao xi 只争朝夕 [天津], 天津干代会东方红画店革命造反委员会, 1967 November 1 (Box-folder 14: 31)
  - Zhong xue dou pi gai 中学斗批改 [北京], 中学红代会海淀委员会教育革命联络站中学斗批改编辑组, 1967 August (Box-folder 14: 32)
  - Zhong xue feng bao 中学风暴 北京, [北京建筑工程学校红卫兵飞虎队], 1967 May 27 (Box-folder 14: 33)
  - Zhong xue feng lei 中学风雷 北京, 首都中等学校红卫兵革命造反联络总站, 1967 January-February (Box-folder 14: 34)
  - Zhong xue feng lei 中学风雷 [天津], 天津市中等学校红卫兵革命造反委员会, 1967 August 1 (Box-folder 14: 35)
  - Zhong xue hong wei bing 中学红卫兵 [北京], 红代会海淀区委员会中学红卫兵报编辑部, 1967 May-October (Box-folder 14: 36)
  - Zhong xue hong wei bing 中学红卫兵 [北京], 红代会清华附中井冈山, 京工附中红旗, 1967 April 30 (Box-folder 14: 37)
  - Zhong xue hong wei bing 中学红卫兵 [南京], 南京中学红卫兵编辑部, 1967 July 30 (Box-folder 14: 38)
  - Zhong xue hong wei bing 中学红卫兵 [天津], 天津市中等学校红卫兵代表大会, 1967 May 27, December 9; 1968 May 13 (Box-folder 14: 39)
  - Zhong xue lun tan 中学论坛 [N.p.], 中学论坛编辑部, 1967 March-April (Box-folder 14: 40)
  - Zhong xue tong xun 中学通讯 [上海], 上海公社编辑部通讯组, 1967 April 28 (Box-folder 14: 41)
  - Zhong xue wen ge bao 中学文革报 [北京], 首都中学生革命造反司令部宣传部, 1967 January-April (Box-folder 14: 42)
  - Zhong xue yun dong 中学运动 [上海], 中学运动编辑部, 1967 March 29, May 8 (Box-folder 14: 43)
  - Zhong yi yao zhan bao 中医药战报 [N.p.], 河北省中医药斗批改总部中医药战报编辑部, 1967 December 1 (Box-folder 14: 44)
  - Zhu chen fu 主沉浮 青岛, 青岛市革命职工总司令, 1968 July 16 (Box-folder 14: 45)
  - Zhu chen fu 主沉浮 [N.p.], 新疆军区生产建设兵团机关主沉浮编辑部, 1967 December 16 (Box-folder 14: 46)
  - Zhua ge ming cu sheng chan zhan bao 抓革命促生产战报 [武汉], 湖北省武汉市抓革命促生产第一线指挥部, 1967 April (Box-folder 14: 47)
  - Zhui qiong kou 追穷寇 [北京], 彻底粉碎刘少奇反革命修正主义路线大会筹备处, 1967 April-June (Box-folder 14: 48)
  - Zhui qiong kou 追穷寇 [N.p.], 河北日报革命造反总部, 1967 June-July (Box-folder 14: 49)
  - Zi liao yu dong tai 资料与动态 [天津], 天津市工农兵砸三日批判毒草影片联络站, 天津市工代会卫东印刷厂无产阶级革命 造反联合指挥部, 1967 September 17 (Box-folder 14: 50)
  - Zun yi 遵义 [天津], 天津东风大学遵义兵团遵义编辑部, 1967 May 28 (Box-folder 14: 51)
  - Zun yi hong qi 遵义红旗 [北京], 人民日报遵义红旗战斗团, 1967 May 20 (Box-folder 14: 52)
  - Zun yi zhan bao 遵义战报 [N.p.], 人民出版社, 农村读物出版社遵义战斗兵团, 1967 February 1 (Box-folder 14: 53)
  - Zuo quan bao 左权报 [N.p.], 中共左权核心小组, 1967 July 10 (Box-folder 14: 54)
- Pamphlets 小册子, 1967-1971 (Box 15)
- Graphics 图画, 1967, undated (Box 15)
  - Bi Fa Liu Shaoqi 笔伐刘少奇 上海市邮电管理局邮政处革命生产小组等, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 37)
  - Che Di Chan Chu Da Du Cao Hei Xiu Yang 彻底铲除大毒草黑修养漫画特刊 上海艺术院校文艺界革命造反司令部, 文化局系统分部主编, undated (Box-folder 15: 38)
  - Cheng Jian Zhan Bao 城建战报 [第6 期漫画专刊] 北京市工代会城建系统大联合筹备小组城建战报编辑部, undated (Box-folder 15: 39)
  - Da Dao Liu Shaoqi 打倒刘少奇 红代会北京矿产学院东方红绘编, undated (Box-folder 15: 40)
  - Da Dao Tao Zhu 打倒陶铸 北京医学院批判陶铸联络站, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 41)
  - Gong Nong Bing 工农兵画报 [创刊号] 工农兵画报编辑部, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 42)
  - Hong Wei Bing 红卫兵画刊 首都红代会首都红卫兵画刊编辑部, undated (Box-folder 15: 43)
  - Kan Jin Zhao 看今朝画刊 [第2期] 上海工人革命造反总司令部美术战线联络站等编, undated (Box-folder 15: 44)
  - Lao San Pian Wan Sui 老三篇万岁 – 毛主席著作画 中央美术学院班系大联合文革代表会红代会, 中央美术学院燎原战斗团, undated (Box-folder 15: 45)
  - Niu Shao Qi Gao Chou Shi 刘少奇狗丑史 上海红卫兵电影制片厂红色造反公社, undated (Box-folder 15: 46)
  - Mei Shu Bing 美术兵 [第二期] 北京师范学院毛泽东思想美术兵, 井冈山公社无名战团合编, undated (Box-folder 15: 47)
  - Mei Shu Zhan Bao 美术战报 [创刊号, 第二, 三期] 美术战报编辑部, undated (Box-folder 15: 48)
  - Qi Hong Tu 起宏图 – 打倒刘少奇画刊 1 上海工人革命造反总司令部静安区分部起宏图报编辑部, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 49)
  - Qian Jun Bang 千钧棒 [第二期] 首都革命造反派千钧棒漫画编辑部, undated (Box-folder 15: 50)
  - She Ying Zhuan Kan 摄影专刊 天津市劳二半八.一八红卫兵, 天津市东方红歌舞团东方红公社, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 51)
- Sound Recordings of the Revolutionary Model Opera 革命样板戏原声碟, 1967-1970s (Boxes 16-18)
  Scope and Contents note
  Includes 52 recordings: 38 ten-inch vinyl sound discs, 3 seven-inch vinyl sound discs, and 11 twelve-inch vinyl sound discs.
  - Flames Hero 火海英雄, 1967 (Box 16)
    Access
    Use copy reference number 2007c53_a_0009519
  - Rent Collection Courtyard 收租院, 1967 (Box 16)
    Use copy reference number: 2007c53_a_0009520
  - Red Lantern 红灯记, 1967 (Box 16)
    Use copy reference number: 2007c53_a_0009518
    General note
    Disc M-819
  - Raid on the White Tiger Regiment 奇袭白虎团, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Taking the Bandits' Stronghold 智取威虎山, 1967 (Box 16)
  - On the Docks 海港, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Chairman Mao's Works Are a Treasure of Revolution 毛主席的书是革命的宝, 1967 (Box 16)
  - A Pure and White Hata for Chairman Mao 洁白的哈达献给毛主席, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Our Great Leader Mao Tse-tung 伟大领袖毛主席, 1970s (Box 16)
  - Chairman Mao's Fighters Are the Closest Followers of the Party 毛主席的战士对党最忠心, 1970s (Box 16)
  - Quotations From Chairman Mao 为毛主席语录谱曲, 1967 (Box 16)
  - The Socialist Road Is the Broadest of All 社会主义道路最宽广, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Eternal Life to Chairman Mao 祝福毛主席万寿无疆, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Sing in Praise of Chairman Mao's Good Fighters 歌唱毛主席的好战士, 1967 (Box 16)
  - Chairman Mao poetry 为毛主席诗词谱曲, 1967 (Box 17)
    Disc M-845
  - Cost Defense Fighters songs 海防战士之歌, 1967 (Box 17)
    Disc M-810
  - Treat the Cadres Properly 必须正确地对待干部, 1967 (Box 17)
    Disc WM-013. Use copy reference number: 2007c53_a_0009524
  - Mao Tse-tung Teachings 毛泽东专辑, 1970s (Box 17)
    Use copy reference number: 2007c53_a_0009525
  - Mao Tse-tung Thought Generates the Strength for Revolution 毛泽东思想是革命力量源泉, 1970s (Box 17)
    Disc M-816
  - Highlights from the White-haired Girl 白毛女, 1967 (Box 17)
    Discs M-817 & M-818
  - Poor Peasants Love Chairman Mao Most 贫下中农最爱毛主席, 1970s (Box 17)
    Use copy reference number: 2007c53_a_0009521
    Disc M-809
    Songs by the Peasants' Amateur Cultural Team of Hopei Province
    Poor and Lower-Middle Peasants Love Chairman Mao Most
    Side 1: 1. Poor and Lower-Middle Peasants Love Chairman Mao Most (Female Voice in Unison) 2. Chairman Mao Puts on His Olive-Green Uniform (Female Voice in Unison) 3. Look at the Well-Grown Crops of Our Team (Male Singing with Acting) 4. We'll Catch Up with Tachai with Great Determination (Female Voice in Unison) 5. Conquer Nature and be Its Master (Female Singing with Acting)
    Side 2: 1. Mao Tse-Tung's Thought Illuminates Our Village (Female Solo) 2. Girls in Our Village are Really Capable (Female Voice in Unison) 3. Eight Sisters-in-Law Take Part in the Spring Ploughing (Female Singing with Acting) 4. We Grow Cotton for the Revolution (Female Singing with Acting) 5. We Are Both Peasants and Militiamen (Song and Dance)
  - Peasants, Workers and Soldiers Pioneer the Revolution 工农兵革命路上打先锋, 1967 (Box 17)
    Disc M-984
  - Chairman Mao's Revolution Line Will Always Lead Us On 毛主席的革命路线指引咱永向前, 1967 (Box 17)
    Disc M-2085
  - The East Is Red 东方红, 1970s (Boxes 17-18)
    Disc XM-1016
  - Sha Chia Bang 沙家浜, 1970s (Box 18)
  - The Red Lantern Peking Opera 红灯记京剧, 1970s (Box 18)
- 2015 incremental materials (Box 19)
  The 2015 incremental materials contain documents relating to revolutionary activities in the Beijing and Shanghai areas and Mao Zedong’s directives to party members and the Red Guards against his political rivals, notably the former chairman of the People’s Republic, Liu Shaoqi, and Liu’s wife, Wang Guangmei.
- 2017 incremental materials (Boxes 20-21)
  Materials not yet described.